1. In your own words, explain what clean code is and why it is important. - Clean code is code that is very easy to read so for example if another developer looked at your code he wouldn't be like "Uhh what does that do?" but he would just read through it and understand every bit. As well, as it being very neat like nested properly and not repeated everywhere.

2. Another object I have in mind if the ECU which is the many cars today and I like to mod my cars so ECU is pretty important and basically if the code wasn't created in an acceptable stand or just bad code the ECU wouldn't be doing a lot which could be things such as controlling the boost of the car, limiting the top speed of the car, and more and that could really hurt people if it wasn't programmed correctly as your throttle response could be very low for example and if you had to accelerate quickly when exiting to the freeway that would be a big problem as someone could hit you from behind because you were accelerating slowly.

3. Code clean or not? Explain and refactor code. - This isn't clean code because they have way to many comments which means that it's hard to understand and they are using just letters which could be hard to understand for others.

FUNCTION convertTemperature(temperature, scale)               
 IF scale = "F" THEN               
 SET convert to (temperature−32) * (5/9)      
 PRINT convert                       
 ELSE IF scale = "C" THEN          
 SET convert to temperature * 1.8000 + 32.00   
 PRINT convert                       
 END IF
END FUNCTION

4. Would you consider the following to be clean code? Explain why or why not. If not, refactor the code. - This code looks to be pretty clean first off because it has the parameters as words not just letters representing and also because it's pretty short and simple to read.

FUNCTION calcPercent(sum, total)
 IF NOT(total = 0) THEN
     SET percentage to sum / total * 100
 ELSE
   PRINT "Sorry, cannot divide by 0"
 END IF

 PRINT percentage
END FUNCTION

5. Using pseudocode, refactor the code for the following examples using the principles you have learned in this checkpoint.

A. FUNCTION checkOutCustomer(subTotal, discountRate, paymentType)
   var total = subTotal * discountRate + (subTotal * tax)
   PRINT "Your total due is: " + total
   	
   IF paymentType = 'CASH' THEN
       CALL getPayment RETURNING amount
       PRINT "Change due: " + amount - total
   ELSE IF paymentType = 'CREDIT CARD' THEN
       PRINT "Your credit card has been charged: " + total
   END IF
END FUNCTION

B. FUNCTION checkoutBook(book, guest)
 IF guest.accountActive AND !guest.hasOverdueBooks AND guest.outstandingFees = 0 THEN
           APPEND book to guest.books
           SET book.status to "Checked Out"
           PRINT "Your books have been issued."
 ELSE
     PRINT "Unable to check out book."
 END IF
END FUNCTION

C. CLASS BankMoney

 FUNCTION displayBalance
    PRINT balance
 END FUNCTION

 FUNCTION deposit(amount)
    SET balance to balance + amount
 END FUNCTION

 FUNCTION withdraw(amount)
     IF balance > amount THEN
       SET balance to balance - amount
     END
 END FUNCTION

 CLASS BankExtras

 FUNCTION creditCardOffer
     IF NOT(customer.hasCreditCard) THEN
         CALL offerCreditCard
     END
 END FUNCTION

 FUNCTION checkStatus
     IF NOT(customer.hasCheckingAccount) THEN
         CALL offerCheckingAccount
     END
 END FUNCTION

 ....
 ....
 ....

END

6. Given an array of integers, find out whether the sum of the integers is a perfect square. If it is a perfect square, return the square root, otherwise return the sum.

function perfectSquare(array) {
  var sum = array.reduce((num1, num2) => num1 + num2);
  if(sum % Math.sqrt(sum) === 0) {
    return Math.sqrt(sum);
  } else {
    return sum;
  }
}
console.log(perfectSquare([2,3,5,-1]));

7. Given an array of integers, find out whether the array contains any duplicate elements. The function should return true if any value appears at least twice in the array, and false if every element is distinct.

function hasNoDuplicates(arr) {
    return arr.every(num => arr.indexOf(num) === arr.lastIndexOf(num));
}

hasNoDuplicates([10, 12, 10, 11, 9])
